Content marketing is at the core of many online marketing campaigns,
内容营销是很多互联网市场营销的关键
and you'll find yourself tasked with reporting on
你会发现你经常需要围绕着内容
a wide variety of metrics surrounding your content.
进行各式各样的指标分析
Now when it comes to our content analysis,
说到内容分析
we're often looking at three areas.
我们通常关注下面三个方面
The first is the performance of our own published content.
第一个是我们自己的发布内容的表现
Things like e-books, blog articles podcasts, videos and presentations.
包括电子书、博客文章、播客、视频、展示等
Second is the performance of our competitor's content.
第二个是竞争对手的内容
We want to evaluate all of the types of content that they're
我们想知道他们都在创作什么类型的内容
building and understand how it's performing and finally,
以及这些内容的表现
the content generated by others about us.
第三个方面 是其他人创作的关于我们的内容
This could be social media mentions or blog articles.
比如社交媒体上的被提及 或者博客推荐文
Now we look at all of this data a variety of different ways.
不同的内容 关注点不一样
For our content, we're trying to understand what's the goal,
对于自家内容 我们需要知道目标是什么
why did we build this content.
为什么创作这些内容
Now when we started making the content,
我们在开始制作内容之前
we should've been establishing what we want to be measuring.
需要确定我们要衡量哪些方面
So we will measure that information basically
所以 这些信息的衡量方式基本与
in the same manner that we measure our owned media.
付费媒体的衡量方式一致
In this case, we're usually interested in many of the same metrics as our website.
很多内容指标也会与网站指标一致
How many people are engaging with this content?
有多少人与内容产生了互动？
How much time are they spending with it?
他们停留了多长时间？
Is this leading to them consuming more content from us?
这是否引导他们消费更多的内容？
We also want to understand how this content is impacting the journey on the funnel.
我们还需要知道某个内容是否影响了客户的漏斗进程
If someone is downloading a piece of content and not doing anything after that download,
如果某个客户下载了某个内容 但是没有后续行动
well, we'd want to look at those metrics and understand why.
那么我们就要关注下相关指标 然后找出为什么
For our competitive content,
对于竞争对手的内容
we typically want to answer a variety of questions such as,
需要回答的典型问题包括
how often is this content being published?
内容发布的频率
Who is the target for this content?
内容的受众
Is this content high-quality?
内容的质量
Who else might be linking to this content?
与内容相关的其他人都有哪些
For that, we're trying to get a gauge of how much this content is
关于最后一个 我们是想知道某个内容是否有其他重要的 KOL
being shared by other prominent sources around the web.
在网上进行了分享 以及分享的次数、表现
We're also interested in what keywords this brand is targeting by that content,
我们也想知道竞争品牌希望通过这个内容 将哪些关键词作为目标
perhaps we're competing on the same keywords or we're
我们可能也在竞价相同的关键词 或者
identifying the white-space for where we want to go where they aren't.
可以发现一些他们尚未发现的机会点
We also want to understand what the purpose of this content is.
同时 也希望了解这个内容的目的是什么
We have to think strategically to understand where in that customer journey
应该用战略性思维来思考 对手品牌将这个内容放置在了
this brand has positioned that content and what they're hoping that content delivers.
客户旅程的哪个步骤 以及他们希望产生什么效果
We also want to take a step at understanding how many people are
我们也希望深入了解有多少人与这个内容
engaging with this content and that it's important to
产生了互动 以及了解是否有任何
understand if there are any influencers or prominent journalists
KOL 或者 著名记者
associated with this content and when it comes to content generated about us,
与这个内容相关 最后 关于别人产生的与我们相关的内容
well we're interested in many of the same questions but also we're really going to be
很多问题是重复的 但是最重要的是要知道
curious about who is writing about us and where's that content showing up.
谁在写我们 以及这个内容的发布渠道
Now there are a couple of tools that help answer these questions.
有几个工具可以帮助回答以上问题
One of my personal favorites is BuzzSumo.
我最喜欢的工具之一是 BuzzSumo
It allows you to analyze what content performs best for any topic or competitor.
它可以帮你分析对于某个话题或者竞争对手 哪个内容表现最好
You can also discover engaging content and outreach opportunities.
你可以发掘最好的互动性内容都有哪些 从而发现机会点
Not only can you identify topics to write about,
你不仅可以发现有什么内容可以写
but you can also see what's already been published on
也可以看到关于某个话题 已发布的内容都有哪些
a particular topic or all of the content published by a particular competitor.
或者你的某个竞争对手的所有已发布内容
This helps you find venues for your content or to
你可以找到发布内容的恰当渠道
identify influencers who might be able to amplify your message.
或者找到可以帮助你扩大宣传的 KOL
Another resource is Cision.
另一个工具是 Cision
This is primarily a database of influencers,
这是 KOL 资源池
so they'll use it to find the right people to connect with and then
可以找到恰当的宣传人选
you can have them distribute your content or your press releases
帮你发布内容或者新闻稿
and they also feature monitoring tools that measure your channel reach and the type
Cision 也提供检测工具 可以检测你的渠道表现
of coverage your content gets across online print and broadcast.
以及你的内容在网上和广播里的覆盖程度
Now going beyond Google Analytics,
除 Google Analytics 之外
you can look at tools like Parsley.
你可以选用 Parsley 之类的工具
This allows you to see how your content is performing in
它可以让你看到内容的实时表现
real-time and easily explore historical trends.
同时很方便地查看历史趋势
This is very popular with publishers who move a lot
这对于发布频率很高的、想每天都能查看流量
of content and want to see traffic daily.
的发布者来说 非常方便
There are lots of pre-built ways to segment this data.
工具也有很多自带的数据分组功能
Now content marketing is proving to be one of
不管是对于大公司还是小公司来说
the best ways to help promote businesses both big and small.
内容营销都是促进业务的最好途径
You can improve the content you create by
你可以通过了解什么类型的内容与你的目标客户相关
understanding what is relevant to your target audience,
来优化你创作的内容
what's answering the most in-demand questions and
什么内容契合了最常见的需求
by keeping on top of what your competitors are doing.
从而保证竞争优势